"NETFLIX
オリジナルシリーズ"
（歩く音）
（春雄(はるお)）日高(ひだか)！
Hidaka!
（明るい音楽）
矢口(やぐち)くん
Oh, Yaguchi.
ビックリした
You startled me!
はは それ餅か？
Are those rice cakes?
新年早々おつかいで
ご苦労なこった
The year just started and you're
already running errands!
私のあげた
手袋してくれてる…
The gloves I made...
He's wearing them.
"Happy New Year"...
明けましておめでとうでしょ
新年のあいさつは
Isn't it what you should say to me now?
ああそうだったな
Yeah, you're right.
明けましておめでとよ
Happy New Year!
あ…どこ行くの これから
So where are you going?
そこのゲームショップだよ
That game shop over there.
ここでは年明けにお年玉
セールを実施してんだよ
There's a New Year's sale
going on right now.
お年玉を頂いた子供達が
目の色変えてやってくる
Such a splendid event.
You can see it in the eyes of all the kids
who got cash as a gift for New Year!
素晴らしいイベントだぜ
俺の目は何色だ 日高！
How do mine look, Hidaka?
（パッ）
なんか汚い
Kind of gross.
こんなにゲームが
激安になるのは
The one day in the entire year
when you can buy games so cheap!
一年でこの日だけなんだよ
ＰＣエンジンのソフトが
TurboGrafx-16 games can get
as low as 50 yen!
最安で50円とかに
なっちゃうんだぜ
- ほら見ろよ
- またペラペラしゃべってる
-Check it out, it's unbelievable!
-He's off again...
By the way.
ところでお前
なんでついて来てんの？
Why'd you come along?
うん…別に
Oh, no reason.
（取る音）
これとか
気になるなーって思って
I was curious about stuff
like this.
おお スーファミの
「モータルコンバット」！
Oh! That's Mortal Kombat, for the SNES!
I wonder how the live-action characters
would fight.
実写の人がどうやって戦うか
気になるし
You... you've really got
an eye for things!
お前…なかなか
見る目があるじゃねぇか
来い日高！
Come, Hidaka!
そのゲームの本物の良さを
伝えずにはいられねぇ！
I have to show you
the true wonders of that game!
どこに行くの矢口くん！
Where are you going, Yaguchi?
オープニングテーマ
'New Stranger'
ORIGINAL WORK BY RENSUKE OSHIKIRI
"ハイスコアガール"
♪終業のチャイムで
走り出す ゼロフレーム♪
♪今日も戦いに
飢えた獣とたわむれる♪
♪ずっと画面の端
待ちながら溜め続けた♪
♪情熱の炎が
西の空染める♪
♪陽の当たる
ステージでは見えない♪
♪小さな想い♪
♪今も街のどこかで
輝いている♪
♪心の奥のゲージを
使うのはいつ？♪
♪デタラメと
何度言われたって♪
♪誰にも
認められなくったって♪
♪止まらない止まれない
この勝負は譲れない♪
♪高く弾くコイン♪
♪表と裏 選び取る選択♪
♪教科書に載ってない
答えを探して♪
♪戦いはずっと続く♪
♪もっと高く♪
♪もっと遠くで♪
♪きっといつか♪
♪また出会う♪
♪デタラメと
何度言われたって♪
♪誰にも
認められなくったって♪
♪止まらない止まれない
この勝負は譲れない♪
"ROUND 5"
（ゲームの音）
う どうしよ…
こんな所来るの初めて…
Oh, boy.
I've never been to a place like this.
学校じゃ禁止されてるのに…
And school forbids it, too...
If we're caught, we can just say
we got lost buying those rice cakes.
もし見つかっても
餅買ってたら
迷い込んだって言えばいいよ
どういう言い訳なの それ…
What kind of excuse is that?
あったあった！
あの筐体を見よ
There it is!
Look at that cabinet!
「モータルコンバット」
専用筐体の存在
The infamous Mortal Kombat cabinet!
（歩く音）
なんかものものしい台だね
It's quite an imposing machine.
タイトルの意味は
命がけの争いだ
The title means:
"A fight where your life is at stake."
危機迫るものを感じるだろ
It practically screams brutality.
この重低音がまた
たまらねぇ物があるんだわ！
And these low bass tones are to die for.
俺の使用キャラはもっぱら
このライデンさんだぜ
There's just one character I use...
Raiden.
（ゲームの音）
（ゲーム）
ファイト！
Fight!
は！　は！
ハイヤ！
- は！
- うわ！
- はあ！
- うお！
- とう！
- うわ！
うわ…シュールな世界
What a surreal world...
なんだか見ちゃいけない物を
見てる気がする
Feels like I'm watching
something forbidden.
これに怖じ気づいてちゃ
一流のゲーマーになれねぇぞ
You have to be able to endure this
if you ever want to be a top-class gamer.
別に一流のゲーマーなんて
目指してないのに
I wasn't exactly aiming
to be a top-class gamer...
ハイヤ！
ねぇ ライデンって人が
飛んでいく時
Hey, so when this Raiden fellow jumps
なんて言ってるの？
what does he say?
What?
え？
- アソビバディー
- うわあ！
アソビバディー
（小春(こはる)）これ
There.
To me, sounds like...
俺にはアソビバディーか
ハルバルデカーに聞こえるぜ
"I sold a baddie!"
or "halberd acorn," maybe.
え…私には
何なんですかーか
Huh? To me, it's more like...
"What was that?"
ライデン頑張れーに
聞こえるんだけど
or "Go get them, Raiden!"
あははは ウソだろ
Yeah, right! How come you're hearing
actual proper sentences?
なんで日本語に
聞こえるんだよ？
You're so silly, Hidaka!
バカだなー 日高は
あははは
バグゴアソビバディー！
"I sold a baddie!"
（ゲーム）ハイヤ！
（春雄）あたっ
Finish him!
フィニッシュヒム！
- スコーピオンウィンズ
- あー
Scorpion wins!
See?
あ ほら
お前が変な質問すっから
やられちまったじゃねぇか
You made me lose
with your weird questions.
次 お前がやってみよ！
Next, you're up.
人のせいにしてからに…
Don't blame it on me.
私には難しそうだけど…
Seems like it'll be hard for me...
大丈夫かな？
Are you sure?
Hmm, I see.
うーん そうだな
初めて回転寿司屋に行って
Like going to a conveyor-belt
sushi place for the first time
いきなりカリフォルニア巻き
食うようなもんだな
and eating a California roll
straight away.
ちょっと…
あんまり無茶させないでよね
Don't drag me into anything reckless.
（ゲームの音）
（ゲーム）
スコーピオン
左ボタンが
ハイパンチ ローパンチ
The left buttons are
for high and low punches,
右ボタンが
ハイキックにローキック
the right buttons are high and low kicks
真ん中のボタンがガードだ
and the middle button is for guarding.
This is really complicated!
ものすごく難しいじゃん！
（ゲーム）
ファイト！
Fight!
お！　セイヤ！
ハイヤ！
ああ…やっぱり順応力に
欠けるもんがあるな日高には
Yeah, looks like you're lacking
in adaptability, after all, Hidaka.
誰かさんとは大違いだぜ
The complete opposite
of a certain someone.
100円使わせておいて
何言ってるのよ
Then why did you make me
waste 100 yen to play?
And who's this "someone"?
誰かさんって誰よ
（ゲーム）
ゲットオーバーヒアー！
スコーピオンウィンズ
Scorpion wins!
Hey, you managed to win
with your signature button-mashing skills.
おや お得意のガチャ戦法で
勝利をおさめたか
だがフィニッシュの究極神拳(きゅうきょくしんけん)
出すまでには及ばねぇだろ
But there's no way
you can finish him with a fatality.
な な 何ィ！
What is this!
（ゲーム）
ああ！
スコーピオンウィンズ！
フェイタリティー
Scorpion wins!
Fatality!
うわ…残酷…
How cruel.
この女 まぐれで
究極神拳を出しやがった
This girl...
She just pulled off a fatality
purely by chance!
この前の
スト２ダッシュといい
Just like last time
in Street Fighter II.
奇跡的なプレイを
見せつけやがったよ
She keeps showing me this miraculous play!
こいつはもしかすると
天性の持ち主なのかも知れん
Perhaps...
Could she have been born
with natural talent?
これ慣れれば何とか行けるね
This is alright
once you get used to it, huh?
いけすかねぇ
Curses!
She possesses exactly
what I don't have!
俺が持ってねぇもんを
持ってやがって…
むぅ…何年ぶりだ
この対抗意識
I haven't felt
this fierce rivalry in years!
あの時の大野(おおの)に対する
嫉妬心が蘇ったようだ
It's like that feeling of jealousy
I had with Ono is back with a vengeance!
こうなったら俺の
If that's how it is
俺なりの天性を
見せつけてやる！
I'll just have to show you my own talent!
（ゲームの音）
- 勝負あり！
- ああああ！
ああああ！　ああああ！
Why? Why!
なんでなんで
なんでだよ！
向こうの対戦の人
物凄く負けて怒ってるけど…
The player over there
seems to be incredibly upset over losing.
ああいうカンシャク持ちほど
負かしがいがあるもんだぜ
It's fun beating someone
with a temper like that.
ヒヒ
ゲーセンは
不良のたまり場ではなく
I'll prove arcades aren't hangouts
for degenerates
アホのたまり場ってことを
証明してやるよ
but, rather, they're for idiots!
しなくてもいいから
そんな証明
I'm fine without seeing that proof.
そんな付け焼き刃の
ナコルルじゃ
You won't win against my Genan
俺の幻庵(げんあん)には敵わねぇぜ
with a gimmicky Nakoruru like that.
どうせ可愛いから選んだんだ
って理由で使ってんだろ
I'm sure you just picked her
because she's cute anyway.
オニャハハハ
愛しのナコルルよ
My beloved Nakoruru,
lend me your strength.
俺に力を貸せ
あと結婚してくれー
Also, marry me!
（ゲームの音）
（ゲーム）一本！
（男）もーなんで！
No! Why? Why?
なんでじゃねぇ
What do you mean, "Why"?
It's because you're being so aggressive
with a short-range character.
そんな攻撃のリーチが短い
キャラで必死に挑むからだ
見てろ あいつの本姓を
むき出しにしてやるからな
Check this out. I'm going to expose him
for what he really is.
鍔迫り合いであえて
武器を手放してからの
I'm going to purposely make it
a close fight, then...
屈辱の手ブラ殺法！
I'll humiliate him
by crushing him with bare hands!
（ゲーム）
- キキキ！
- ああ！
ヒヒヒ！
幻庵のスライディングキック
地獄を侮るなかれ
Don't underestimate the hell
that's Genan's sliding kick spam.
相手のパワーゲージと共に
理性もガシガシ削ってやるぜ
Reason slips away
just as quickly as your power gauge.
初心者の私でも見てて分かる
Even as a first-timer,
I can tell by watching.
矢口くんの底意地の悪さが
ゲームから伝わってくる…
Yaguchi's ill will
is coming through in the game!
やだー！
やだやだー！
それではとって置きの
ビックリ技をお見舞いしよう
And now for the cherry on top,
I'll hit him with my final surprise move.
Genan's throw ability, the super combo
幻庵投げ技 幻庵殺爪陣(げんあんさっそうじん)
からの超連打による
the "Genan Killer Claw Formation"!
Maximum damage!
超絶ダメージ！
（ゲーム）勝負あり！
（男）なんじゃそりゃー
（タン）
卑怯やんけー！
見たか日高よ 俺の神技！
Did you see my godly skill, Hidaka?
これで俺は
何十連勝もするんだぜ！
I'll win over and over with this.
お前にもらった
手袋のおかげで
Thanks to the gloves you gave me,
I can make it a super combo.
超連打が可能になったんだが
おかげでほら…
もうボロボロだ
But, look...
It's left them all tattered.
う…
こんちくしょーめがー
You son of a--
てめぇなんざボコボコの
ギタギタにしてやるよ！
I'll beat the living daylights out of you!
来やがったぜ
Here he comes.
When they can't win at a game,
they resort to a direct confrontation.
これこそゲームで勝てんと
直接勝負を挑む
ゲーマーの真の姿だ！
It's the gamer's true nature!
（男）ちきしょう
なめやがってよ…
You little--
Quit looking down on me!
（男性）
ゲーマー同士のケンカは
Fights between gamers
お互い直接の殴り合いに
慣れていないために
often start as a battle
to throw each other down
始まったはいいが
but they will devolve
into a standard mud-wrestle.
単なる泥仕合になることが
よくあったという
（男）
何やってんだお前ら
What the heck are you guys doing?
（歩く音）
ゲームバカの一方通行男…
That one-track-mind gamer idiot...
陰険プレイ…
Underhanded play...
Using the gloves I gave him for that...
あげた手袋をあんなにして…
あげくに喧嘩…
Even getting in a fight.
バカ男！
新年早々嫌な気分…
Dumb boys.
The New Year is already ruined.
I hate him.
嫌い！
あんな男 大嫌い！
I hate that boy!
"日高商店"
HIDAKA SHOP
（静かな音楽）
But...
でもマイペース過ぎる性格は
前から分かってたのよね
I knew all along he did things
his own way.
ゲームの事となると
妙に意固地になる所とか…
Like getting weirdly stubborn
when it comes to games.
そういえばお年玉セール
やってるゲームショップで
Actually...
Since he took me along
to that arcade
私をゲームセンターに
連れてったばかりに
he didn't get to buy anything
at that New Year's sale...
何も買えてなかったよね
当初の目的が頭からスッポリ
抜け出ちゃったのかな
He completely forgot
about his original goal.
なんか悪い事
しちゃったかしら
I wonder if that was my fault.
"幻庵 お見事！"
右手の手袋が
壊れても大丈夫！
Even if the right glove falls apart,
it's fine.
右手の手袋が
壊れても大丈夫！
I can still super-combo if I turn the left
inside-out and wear it on the right.
左手の手袋を裏返しにして
はめれば連打可能よ！
どうでもいいか
矢口くんなんか…
Whatever. I don't care about him.
"翌日"
THE NEXT DAY
（歩く音）
小春 外にいるの お前の
ボーイフレンドじゃないかね
Koharu, isn't that your boyfriend
out there?
なんだか凄く
深刻そうな顔してたけど
He was making a really serious face.
Wh-- ... boyfriend?
ちょっ…
ボーイフレンドって…
No way, Yaguchi?
ウソ…矢口くん？
まぁ どうせいつも通り
ゲームやりに来ただけでしょ
Well, I'm sure he's just here
to play games as usual.
（ゲームの音）
うわ 本当だ
思いつめた表情…
Dad was right, he looks deep in thought.
まさか私が昨日
怒って帰ったから
Could it be he's worried
because I went home
それを気にして…
in a huff yesterday?
って私の思い上がりだよね
No, I'm just imagining it.
下にいる変な男はそんな気を
使う人じゃないはずだし
That weirdo down there
wouldn't worry about that stuff.
ファネッフー
ほら やっぱり
ゲームしに来たんだ
See, he's just here to play games.
多分スーパー
ストリートファイター２ね
Probably Street Fighter II:
The New Challengers.
（ゲーム）
は！
ファネッフー
ガイルっていう
アメリカ人の…
Guile, the American.
（ゲーム）
ユーウィン！
絶好調みたいだね
たぶん…
Sounds like he's on a winning streak.
このゲームは
あまり知らないけど
I don't know much about that game
but I can easily tell he's winning
矢口くんがものすごく
勝ち進んでるのがよく分かる
over and over again.
（ゲーム）
ファネッフー
必死に攻防してる音ね
The sound of a fight going
back and forth.
外はものすごく
冷えるだろうに…
It must be really cold outside.
ゲームってのはここまで
情熱を向けられる物なんだ
Is he that passionate about playing games?
こんなに熱中できる物が
あるのって羨ましい
I'm jealous of...
his devotion to it.
あれ？
うわっうわっ…
外ふぶいてるじゃん
There's a blizzard out there!
（吹雪の音）
さすがにこんな天候じゃ
家に帰ってるよね
I'm sure he's gone home
with weather like this.
ていうか
いたらちょっと引く
Honestly, I'd be scared if he hasn't.
（ボタンの音）
はっ！
バカバカバカ…バカじゃん！
Dummy, dummy, dummy, you dummy!
こんな極寒の中で
風邪引くじゃん！
You're going to catch
a cold in this weather!
でももしかすると
But, what if...
私が出て来るのを
待ってたりして…
he's waiting for me to come out there?
ってバカ！
それが思い上がりなのよ
No, I'm being stupid,
that's just my imagination again.
But, if he would call out to me...
でも呼ばれたら別…
If he asked me, I'd head out there
呼ばれたら全然普通に
パッと顔出せるのに…
like it was nothing.
（春雄）
日高ーいるかー
Hidaka, you there?
Want to play games together?
一緒にゲームやらねぇか？
なんてこと言ってきたら
一緒にゲームやれるのに…
Had he said something like that
I'd play in an instant.
This is bad!
ダメだ…一人の変な男が
気になって気になって
I can't stop thinking
about this weirdo boy!
I can't take it!
し…辛抱たまらん
ファネッフー
-Yaguchi...
-Hidaka?
- や 矢口くん…
- 日高！
こ こんな吹雪の中…
バ バカじゃないの…
You're here in a blizzard...
Are you stupid?
おう！
俺はバカだともよ
Yeah! I guess I'm pretty stupid.
それを言いに来たってのか
You here just to tell me that?
ち 違う
No, no.
あったかいお茶
持って来たのよ
I bought you some hot tea.
か 風邪引くと
いけないから…
I don't want you catching a cold.
My hands are busy right now.
Can you help me drink it?
今 手が離せないから
飲ませてくれねぇか
- なんなのこの人
- あー
What's with him?
- ホント変わってる
- ごくごく
He's so strange.
Isn't that hot?
熱くないのかな
うがぁー
それより矢口くん
今日はずっとここにいるけど
So, Yaguchi.
I'll be here all day.
ね 私に何か
用があったのかな？
So if you had business with...
日高に用？
用は特にないな
Business with you?
No business in particular, nope.
それより見ろ！
More importantly, look!
今現在叩き出している
この高得点を！
I'm blowing out all the other high scores!
今日は日高んちの
筐体全部のハイスコアを
Today I'm going to fill the Hidaka cabinet
with high scores under "Y-A-G"!
ＹＡＧで
埋め尽くしてやるんだ
この雪の日だと今日なら
他の邪魔が入らねぇだろ
On a snowy day like this,
there'll be no interruptions.
まさに最高のマーキング
日和りってわけだぜ
It's the perfect day to mark territory!
He's truly unshakable.
本当ブレない人…
でもムカつくから
電源落としちゃえ
I'll cut the power
since he's ticking me off!
（ブッ）
あああっ！
"ハイスコアガール"
HI SCORE GIRL
（ドン）
（ドドン）
（女子達）
キャー
（パッ）
（男子達）
うおおおー
FEBRUARY 14
"２月14日"
（静かな音楽）
春雄の奴 欠席か
Haruo's absent, huh?
バレンタインデーの日に
風邪で休むなんてナウいぜ
Catching a cold on Valentine's Day?
Now that's edgy.
ま あいつがチョコなんて
もらえるわけねぇか
Well, it's not like he'd get chocolate
from anyone anyway.
That's true, but even for him
there's the smallest chance...
そうだけど
あいつにも もしかしたら
少ない可能性が…
もらえるとしても
バカ女だろうな
You'd have to be the dumbest of broads
to give chocolate to that dummy.
あんなバカに
チョコあげるバカは
そのバカ女は
ここにおりますよ…
That dumb broad is right here.
Though it's platonic chocolate.
義理…だけど
（タン）
もらってちょうだい
宮尾(みやお)くん！
Please accept this, Miyao.
鬼塚(おにづか)手作り画面チョコレート
An Onizuka hand-made chocolate.
もちろん本命
Of course, non-platonic!
つまり性的なアピールも
含まれてるって事よ
That is to say, all my sex appeal went
into making this.
そのチョコは食べるけど
I'll eat the chocolate
鬼塚さんの要求は
叶えられないよ
but I can't reciprocate your feelings.
じゃ じゃあ好きな子の
タイプを教えてちょーだいよ
Then tell me the type of girl you're into!
私もそうなるよう
頑張るかも知れないから
I might just do my best to be like that.
清楚で無口で
奇麗な子が夢だな…
My dream girl would be tidy,
reserved, and pretty...
よしなる！　なるっ！
Got it.
That's what I'll become!
覚悟しとけや
この面喰い野郎！
You better be ready
you shallow, chomping womanizer!
はっ うん
- うーん
- 面喰い…
Shallow, chomping...
（風の音）
（歩く音）
（静かな音楽）
ずうずうしいかな
Is this shameless of me?
たかが義理チョコ渡すだけで
家に押しかけるの…
Can I intrude into his home to give him
a platonic Valentine gift?
ポストにでも入れておこ
Maybe I'll put it in the mail.
当日渡さなきゃいけないって
わけじゃないんだけど
It's not like I can't just give it
to him tomorrow.
なぜかこういうのって
But something like this
just feels wrong to wait
till the day after.
当日に渡さなきゃって
思っちゃうのよね
It's the first time I've given
someone chocolate.
人にあげるの初めてだけど
確かここだっけ
I think this is the place.
本当にうちから
近いトコだったんだ
It really is close to my house.
うちの店にしょっちゅう
ゲームやりに来るわけだね
He is always at our shop
playing games, after all.
だから風邪引くのよ
That's why he caught a cold.
矢口くん 寝てるのかな？
I wonder if Yaguchi is sleeping.
（ゲームの音）
あっ 寝てない！
No, he's not!
かすかに聞こえる
この独特なゲーム音
I can faintly hear those
distinct video-game sounds.
He's playing
あの人 風邪引いて
休んでるのにゲームしてる
even though he should be resting?
- あら 春雄に何か用？
- あ…
My! Are you here to see Haruo?
何も言わなくていいわ
Not a word.
今日が何の日か分かれば
察しがつくって話よ
No need. I know what day it is.
さ 遠慮なく
上がってちょうだい！
Come on, feel free to come in.
あ でも矢口くん
風邪じゃ…
But... doesn't Yaguchi have a cold?
そう 確かに朝は
That's right. He was certainly suffering
this morning when I called the school.
風邪で辛そうだから
学校に電話入れたの
But the moment I ended the call...
でもその電話を終えた瞬間に
ぴょーんって
元気になっちゃってさー
Boom!
He sprung right back to life!
若くて可愛いお母さんだな
What a young, cute mother.
（ガラッ）
お邪魔します
I'm coming in.
あっ！
It's not what it looks like!
ち 違うんだ
これは…その…
This... I was...
"「源平討魔伝(げんぺいとうまでん)」"
鎌倉幕府が誰だったのか
I was playing The Genji and Heike Clans
"「源平討魔伝(げんぺいとうまでん)」"
歴史の勉強を
してた所なんだ
to study the history of
the Kamakura shogunate!
I was going to defeat
the last boss, Yoritomo, as a quiz!
ラスボスの頼朝(よりとも)を倒すべく
確かめに行ってたんだ
But you know the answers.
知ってんじゃん
用ってわけじゃないんだけど
It's not super important
風邪って言ってたから
様子見に来たんだ
but I heard you had a cold
so I came to check on you.
And I brought these, too.
ついでにコレとコレ
（カサ）
おお 今月の
「ゲーメスト」じゃんか
Oh! It's this month's Gamest!
You were really paying attention, Hidaka!
よく気付いてくれたな
日高！
うんーさてさて
今月の特集は…
Now, let's see...
what's featured this month?
あーはいはいはい
-Ah, yes, yes, I see...
-Well, I'll be off, then--
- なるほど
- じゃ私はこれで…
（タラーン）
じゃん！
Ta-da!
春雄ママの
おもてなしデザート
Mama Haruo's Welcome Dessert!
The pancakes you see in the manga!
マンガで出てくる
ホットケーキよ！
ダメダメ
帰らせないんだからね
Sorry, dear! I can't let you leave.
うちの春雄んトコにこんな
可愛い子が来たんだもの
Such a cute girl came to visit
my Haruo, after all.
あ ありがとうございます
Thank you.
またお袋…
しゃしゃり出て来たからに…
Again, Mom comes butting in.
思春期の男女が
一つの部屋に…
A pubescent boy and girl
in the same room...
What are you saying?
Hurry up and get out!
何言ってんだよ
早く出てけよ！
トレンディードラマの
見すぎで
She watches all these trendy dramas
and gets weird ideas in her head.
妙な妄想しやがる
ったく
Jeez.
- ふふっ
- おっ お袋！
Ah, Mom!
- ひゃっひゃひゃー
- 何がしてぇんだよ おい！
What are you doing?
あ 怖い怖い！
You're being scary!
I said that's scary!
怖いって！
そんな羨望の眼差しで
覗いたって
No point in peeking in here
in anticipation like that!
何もねぇんだからな
どうやったんだ今の？
How were you even doing that?
（ガラッ）
ああ クラクラするぜ
Ah, I'm dizzy.
せっかくゲームのおかげで
体調がよくなってきたのに
I'd just started feeling better
from playing games.
なんかごめんね
I'm sorry...
それ食べたら
帰っておくれよ…な？
You head home
once you've eaten that, okay?
My mom will keep prying
into everything, otherwise.
お袋があれこれ
詮索してうるさいから
うん
あ…
うわ すごいゲーム機！
So many consoles!
矢口くん 律義に箱とか
取っとくタイプなんだ
So, you're the responsible type who keeps
the boxes, Yaguchi?
あたりめぇよ
Of course!
しかもゲームが終わったら
And when I'm done playing, I make sure
to put them back in their boxes.
出しっぱなしにしないで
ちゃんと箱に入れるんだぜ
意外と几帳面なんだね
You're surprisingly meticulous.
ふふ…今にして思えば
Perhaps I did it to show off
this spectacle to someone someday.
誰かにその光景を見せたくて
そうしてきたのかもな
- 俺のコレクション見るか？
- うん
Want to see my collection?
Yeah!
（明るい音楽）
どうよ？
How about it? I was frugal with the money
I got for buying textbooks
参考書を買う
金を惜しんで買った
and bought these, pieces of my very soul!
俺の魂の一部達だ！
Oh? TurboGrafx-16?
へぇ ＰＣエンジン
変なゲームばっかりだね
They're all weird games.
Don't call them weird games.
変なゲーム言うなや
まぁ 間違ってはいないが
Though you're not wrong.
"「地獄めぐり」"
タイトーの「地獄めぐり」
Taito's Bonze Adventure.
A game where you venture to hell
to help Enma who's gone insane.
乱心したエンマ様を
何とかするため
地獄をかけめぐるゲームだぜ
What in the world happened to Enma?
エンマ様に
何があったんだろうね
ＰＣエンジンソフトには
There are lots lot of side-scrolling
action games for the TurboGrafx-16.
横スクロールアクションが
とにかく多くてな
ゲームが素人のお前でも
すぐにできる物ばかりだ
They're all games even an amateur like you
could pick up easily.
Want to try?
- やってみっか？
- うん
Yeah, but I'd like you to play
and I'll watch from behind.
でも矢口くんがやってるの
後ろから見てたい
- よーし
- いひっ
Got it.
（ゲーム）
ベラボー べラボー！
So, it's not just the hero's limbs
手足だけじゃなく
首も伸びるヒーローなんて
but his neck extends, as well?
That's almost too novel an idea.
発想が斬新すぎるわね
Bravoman.
「超絶倫人(ちょうぜつりんじん)ベラボーマン」
ゲーマの心をくすぐる
良ゲーさ
A game that tugs
at a gamer's heartstrings.
矢口くん これはどんな
ホラーゲームなの？
Yaguchi, what kind of
horror game is this?
You mean KiKi KaiKai?
「寄々怪界(ききかいかい)」な
実はシューティングゲームだ
It's actually a shooting game.
And this?
これはこれは？
どんなＲＰＧ？
What kind of RPG is it?
「ドラゴンスピリット」
シューティングゲームさ
Dragon Spirit.
That's a shooting game, too.
"「源平討魔伝(げんぺいとうまでん)
巻ノ弐(かんのに)」"
これは…
「源平討魔伝」でしょ
This one is The Genji
and the Heike Clans, right?
それの続編「巻ノ弐」だぜ
It's the sequel, Samurai-Ghost.
この存在がＰＣエンジン
ユーザーである事に
It's not an exaggeration to call that
title a gem among TurboGrafx-16 users.
誇りを持たせたと言っても
過言じゃねぇ
へへっ
ってな具合でよ
Well, that's the gist.
俺一人でやってると
永遠にやっちまうから
If I play this on my own,
I won't ever stop.
あとは一人で
勝手にやってくれや
Go ahead and play the rest on your own.
えー
Huh?
うん…
（ボタンの音）
ああ
I got too worked up
and got dizzy again.
なんだか張り切りすぎて
目が回ってきたぜ
ずっとゲームしてたせいで
熱が戻っちまったか？
Did the fever come back
from playing all these games?
（ゲームの音）
お？
あ！
（効果音）
（ゲームの音）
Of all the games...
よりによって日高の奴
「功夫(クンフー)」をやるとは…
She chooses to play China Warrior...
I wonder...
あいつ
（悲しい音楽）
今頃何やってんのかね…
Just what is that girl
up to now?
あれから２年
It's been two years since then.
今やゲーセンは
すっかり格闘ゲームブームだ
Now the arcades are
in a complete fighting-game boom.
春雄
Haruo, why do you play Street Fighter II
like you're avenging your family?
そんな親の仇みたいに
スト２やる理由ってなんだ？
理由か…理由はある
Why?
There's a reason.
そう 俺は
ウカウカしてられねぇ
I can't lose focus.
あいつと次会った時
互角に戦うためにも…
The next time I meet her,
our fight has to be on equal footing.
久しぶりに対戦してぇな…
あいつと…
I haven't yearned to fight
her again like this in a while.
（歩く音）
矢口くん 後半すごく
大人しくなったような…
Yaguchi got really quiet
later on in my visit.
無理させて
悪い事しちゃったな
I guess I asked a little much of him.
Spending time with him today
made it clear.
今日 一緒にいて分かった
矢口くんは私の事なんて
全然見てないってこと…
Yaguchi isn't looking at me at all.
But, still...
それでも…
この気持ちは曲げたくない
I don't want to give up this feeling.
（カタカタ）
おセンチになってる
場合じゃねぇ
It's no time to get sentimental.
こっそり購入した
スーファミ版スト２ターボで
I've got to train with this secret SNES
version of Super Street Fighter II Turbo.
修業しねぇと
いつかあいつが
俺の前に現れるその日まで
All I can do is be diligent
until the day
精進あるのみだぜ
she eventually appears before me again.
（ゲームの音）
（ゲーム）
ジャパン！
（飛行機の音）
お嬢様ー
お久しぶりでございます！
Young Miss, it's been so long!
再びお目にかかるこの日を
どんなに待ちわびたことか…
How I've waited for the day
I might lay eyes upon you once more.
またお嬢様の運転手を
務めさせてもらう事が
I'm so happy to be able to work
as your driver again.
嬉しくて
夢を見てるようです
It's like I'm dreaming!
Come on, I'm sure you're tired
from your long journey.
ささ 長旅でお疲れでしょう
ゆっくり休んで
Please relax and take your time
getting used to life here again.
またこちらの生活に
慣れていかないとですね！
ぐっうー
♪10カウントで終わる♪
♪世界はモノクロだった♪
エンディングテーマ
'放課後ディストラクション'
♪朝の鍛錬
いちにのさんしで♪
♪ゴーゴー学校
コケコッコー♪
♪ＮＡＳＡの陰謀
しのごの言わずに♪
♪東京観光 大統領♪
♪登下校は高級車で♪
♪挨拶はごきげんよう♪
♪ジョン・レノンは
殺されたの♪
♪退屈な授業
エスケープ気取って♪
♪10カウントで終わる♪
♪はずだった
世界が色づく♪
♪エンカウントで
コンティニュー♪
♪小さな革命だった♪
♪放課後♪
♪ディストラクション♪
Subtitle translation by
Helen O'Horan
"「ファンタジー
ゾーン」
1986年アーケード稼働"
"「ファンタジー
ゾーン」
1986年アーケード稼働"
（春雄）
ガキの頃は仲良く
一緒にやってたのに
We got along well as little kids
（春雄）
ガキの頃は仲良く
一緒にやってたのに
（春雄）
ガキの頃は仲良く
一緒にやってたのに
"株式会社セガ・
インタラクティブ"
いつの間にか
離れ離れになっててさ
but we got separated along the way.
いつの間にか
離れ離れになっててさ
"「バブルボブル」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社タイトー"
"「バブルボブル」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社タイトー"
Now, we finally meet again.
"「バブルボブル」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社タイトー"
そしてついに再会する
"「バブルボブル」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社タイトー"
But we can't just go back
to the time when we were younger.
"「バブルボブル」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社タイトー"
けど ガキの頃には
簡単には戻れねぇ
"「R-TYPE」
1987年アーケード稼働"
な リュウとケンだって
Hey, didn't Ken and Ryu have
a similar experience?
な リュウとケンだって
"アイレムソフト
ウェアエンジニアリング
株式会社"
"アイレムソフト
ウェアエンジニアリング
株式会社"
"アイレムソフト
ウェアエンジニアリング
株式会社"
そういう事
あったんじゃねぇか？
♪10カウントで終わる♪
♪はずだった
世界が色づく♪
♪エンカウントで♪
"日本語字幕 パク・スミン"